

• Mexico City, Mexico

in Ricardo Ruiz

@ gaanzz11@gmail.com

gitlab.com/Ricardoengitlab

github.com/Ricardoengithub

(+52) 5620278551

SUMMARY

I have 6 years of programming experience and 2 years of professional experience in sectors such as insurance, real estate and e-commerce. I mainly work with Javascript (with experience in React), Python (with experience in Django) and Java. As a Computer Scientist I can get involved in any area of development including research however I am mainly interested in the front end.

EXPERIENCE

Front end developer at GNP Seguros

April 2021 - February 2022

UI for an insurance company where agents can fill all data required for several types of insurances based on their client's needs to get the cost and try to make an offer.

React / Redux / Material UI / Team Management

Full stack developer at M22

October 2020 - February 2021

UI for a real estate company where people can view details and availability of several places for make purchase agreement. All the data updates in real time and the content is modified from a Content Management System(CMS).

React / Strapi JS / QGIS / GraphQL / PostgreSQL

Full stack developer at Ultra maratón sierra mixe

January 2020 - September 2020

This is a client's project on the automation of the processes involved in the realization of a marathon race such as registration, marketing and payment.

React / Google Firebase / Bootstrap

Full stack developer

Summer 2018

Mobile application for Android to help teachers and students to know if a number is prime or not, also the app can give you the list of prime numbers in a range and calculate the Euler's totient function. Android Studio / Flutter / Dart

EDUCATION

BS in Computer Science (2017 - 2022)

National Autonomous University of Mexico

Relevant Coursework: Automata Theory, Computer Architecture, Algorithm Analysis, Artificial Intelligence, Software Engineering, Operating Systems, Data Structures, Relational Databases, Distributed Computing, Geographic Information Systems

GPA: 85

TECHNICAL SKILLS

4 years **Python**, **Java**, **HTML**, **CSS**

3 years React, Javascript, Flutter, Dart, Oracle SQL 2 years C#, Unity, Racket, C, Django, Haskell

1 year Gatsby, GraphQL, Redux 6 months Nextjs, Golang, Strapi

LANGUAGES

Spanish - Native

English - Conversational French - Intermediate Portuguese - Basic